欢迎光临年轻人的酒店空间，感受不一样的电影时光！
m 0 0 b 1 -1 2 -2 4 -1 b 7 1 3 2 5 5 b 6 7 8 7 9 5 l 15 -6 b 18 -7 20 -6 20 -3 b 19 -1 17 2 17 4 b 16 7 20 7 21 6 b 22 4 23 2 25 -1 b 27 -2 29 -1 29 1 b 29 2 28 3 29 5 b 30 7 32 7 33 6 b 34 5 34 4 35 3 b 37 2 39 3 39 5 b 39 6 38 8 37 9 b 34 13 29 13 25 9 b 22 13 17 13 13 9 b 10 13 3 13 0 8
原创翻译  双语字幕
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 50 0 l 179 0 b 208 0 229 21 229 50 l 229 179 b 229 208 208 228 179 228 l 50 228 b 21 228 0 208 0 179 l 0 50 b 0 21 21 0 50 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻译     吃冰棒  苏小黛  Carolingo  海云生
翻译     不见DIO  VioletCheng  kathy567  子V
翻译     米糊  tong大梨  TracyOY  glida
校对     布塔诚荐
时间轴   JOJO·查  没有影子
时间轴   caroline  紫夏  壬虚浪影
后期     渔夫
东法肯海姆
总监     布塔
乔乔·贝茨勒
Jojo Betzler.
十岁
Ten years old.
今天  你将加入青年团的
Today, you join the ranks of the Jungvolk
一次非常特别的周末训练
in a very special training weekend.
训练会非常艰苦
It's going to be intense.
但今天  你就是一个男人了
But today, you become a man.
我发誓将我所有的精力和力量
I swear to devote all my energies and my strength
献给祖国的救世主  阿道夫·希特勒
to the savior of our country, Adolf Hitler.
我愿意为他献上我的生命
I am willing and ready to give up my life for him.
愿上帝保佑我
So help me God.
这就对了
Yes, that's right.
-乔乔·贝茨勒  你的头脑是  -蛇的头脑
- Now, Jojo Betzler, what is your mind? - Snake mind.
-乔乔·贝茨勒  你是身体是  -狼的身体
- And, Jojo Betzler, what is your body? - Wolf body.
-乔乔·贝茨勒  你的胆子是  -豹子的胆子
- Jojo Betzler, what is your courage? - Panther courage.
-乔乔·贝茨勒  你的灵魂是  -德国人的灵魂
- And, Jojo Betzler, what is your soul? - A German soul.
很好  你准备好了
Yeah, man. You're ready.
阿道夫
Adolf.
我觉得我不行
I don't think I can do this.
什么  你当然可以
Was? Of course you can.
没错  你身板子是有点弱  不受人待见
Sure, you're a little bit scrawny and a bit unpopular
你都十岁了
and you can't tie your shoelaces
连鞋带都不会系
even though you're ten years old.
但你还是我认识的最棒的  最忠心的小纳粹
But you're still the bestest, most loyal little Nazi I've ever met.
更别提你真的很帅气
Not to mention the fact you're really good-looking.
所以  你要大胆走出去
So, you're gonna get out there
你会过得很愉快的  好吗
and you're gonna have a great time, okay?
-好  -这就对了  好了
- Okay. - That's the spirit. Okay.
向我致敬
Heil me, man.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
什么  不够响亮
What? You can heil me better than that.
-希特勒万岁  -不对...
- Heil Hitler. - No...
放开来  别过脑子
Just throw it away. Don't even think about it.
-希特勒万岁  -不对  你顾虑太多了
- Heil Hitler. - No, you're overthinking it.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
"希塔勒"万岁
Heil "Hitterler."
希塔勒是谁  你会说德语吗
Who's "Hitterler?" Do you even speak German?
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
万岁不是这样说的  应该这样  万岁
That's not a heil. This is a heil. Heil!
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler! - Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler!
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
-对了  你学会了  -希特勒万岁...
- That's it. You've got it. - Heil Hitler...
-祝今天愉快  -希特勒万岁
- Have a great day! - Heil Hitler!
你会是最棒的  希特勒万岁
You're gonna be the best. Heil Hitler!
-希特勒万岁  -你可以的  希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler! - You can do it. Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler! - Heil Hitler! Heil Hitler!
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
? Oh, komm doch, komm zu mir ?
Komm, gib mir deine Hand - The Beatles
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
? Du nimmst mir der verstand ?
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler.
? Oh, komm doch, komm zu mir ?
? Komm, gib mir deine hand ?
? Oh, du bist so sch?n ?
? Sch?n wie ein diamant ?
希特勒万岁  希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler.
? Ich will mit dir gehen ?
希特勒万岁  希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler. Heil Hitler.
? Komm, gib mir deine hand ?
-希特勒万岁  约克  -希特勒万岁  乔乔
- Heil Hitler, Yorki. - Heil Hitler, Jojo.
你准备好度过有史以来最棒的周末了吗
Are you ready for the best weekend ever?
准备好了
Yes, I am.
咱们走
Let's go.
? Das war noch nie bei einer anderen ?
? Einmal so, Einmal so ?
? Einmal so ?
? Oh, du bist so sch?n ?
? sch?n wie ein diamant ?
希特勒万岁
? Ich will mit dir gehen ?
? Komm, gib mir deine hand ?
万岁  万岁  万岁
Heil! Heil! Heil!
乔乔兔
大伙  希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler, guys.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler!
欢迎参加希特勒青年团周末训练
Jungvolk, welcome to the Hitlerjugend training weekend.
在这里  你们将成长为大人
In which we will make men and women of you all.
我是克伦森多夫上尉
My name is Captain Klenzendorf.
你们可以叫我克上尉
You may call me Captain K.
克上尉
Captain K.
好了  这位是芬克尔下级军官
Ja. And this is Sub-Officer Finkel.
这位是福来林·拉姆
This is Frülein Rahm.
大家好  希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler, everyone.
简单介绍一下我自己  我是谁
So a little about me. Who am I?
我为什么来跟一群乳臭未干的小不点训话
And why am I here talking to a bunch of little titty-grabbers
而不是带领我的人战死沙场
instead of leading my men into battle towards glorious death?
问得好
Great question.
我在大落败行动中
I've asked it myself
遭遇了一场完全可以避免的敌军袭击
every day since Operation Screw Up
失去了一只完好的眼睛
where I lost a perfectly good eye in
自那以后我每天都这么问自己
a totally preventable enemy attack.
我的上级是这么说的
And according to my superiors,
你需要两只眼睛才能在战争中起作用
you need two eyes to be a meaningful part of the war effort.
有两只眼睛的人能做到这个吗
Can two-eyed people do this?
-老天  -接下来的两天中
- Jesus. - Over the next two days,
你们这些小鬼将会体验到
you little critters will get to experience
伟大的德国军队每天都会经历的事
some of the things that the mighty German army goes through every day.
即便看上去局面对我国很不利
And even though it would appear our country's on the back foot
而且我们也真的无望赢得这场战争的胜利
and there really isn't much hope in us winning this war,
很显然  我们做得还不错
apparently we're doing just fine.
不管怎样  我们给所有人都发了
Anyway. You boys have all been issued
一把德国青年团匕首
with your Deutsches Jungvolk daggers.
这些匕首是非常特别且昂贵的武器
These are very special and expensive weapons.
千万别搞丢了
You should never be without them.
还有别捅伤自己人
And don't try to stab each other.
不准捅人
No stabbing!
No stabbing.
这是你们迈上成长道路的第一步
This is your first step towards being men.
今天男生将参与
Today you boys will be involved
行军  刺刀演习
in such activities as marching, bayonet drills,
扔手榴弹  挖洞  看地图  防毒
grenade-throwing, trench-digging, map-reading, gas defense,
伪装  埋伏技术
camouflage, ambush techniques,
作战演习  开枪以及爆破此类的活动
war games, firing guns, and blowing stuff up.
女生则会练习重要的女性职责
The girls will practice important womanly duties
例如处理伤口  整理床铺
such as dressing wounds, making beds,
还有学习如何受孕
and learning how to get pregnant.
我为德国生了十八个孩子
I've had 18 kids for Germany.
这年头当女孩多么美好啊
Such a great year to be a girl.
好了  开始吧
All right. Let's get to it.
冲啊
Come on.
走
Go!
我的老天爷
God help me.
? Well, when I'm lyin' in my bed at night ?
I Don't Wanna Grow Up - Tom Waits
上  上  上
Go, go, go!
? I don't want to grow up ?
? Nothin' ever seems to turn out right ?
三  二  一  卍字
Three, two, one, swastika!
? How do you move in a world of fog ?
? That's always changing things ?
加油  使劲  加油
Come on! Pull it! Come on!
? Makes me wish that I could be a dog ?
? Well, when I see the price that you pay ?
? I don't want to grow up ?
? I don't ever want to be that way ?
? Seems like folks turn into things ?
-了结了它  -不  别
- Now finish him. - Don't, no, no!
? That they'd never want ?
? The only thing to live for is today ?
-獠牙  -獠牙  对
- Fangs. - Fangs, ja.
犹太人
-蛇舌  -蛇舌  很好
- Serpent tongue. - Serpent's tongue, ja.
-还有鳞片  -没错  鳞片
- Scales. - Ja, scales.
很久很久以前  有个犹太人跟鱼交配过
Because, once upon a time, a Jewish man mated with a fish.
我们雅利安人比其他任何种族
We, Aryans, are one thousand times
都要文明和先进一千倍
more civilized and advanced than any other race.
现在  把东西都收好  孩子们
Now, get your things together, kids.
该去烧点书了
It's time to burn some books.
耶
Yeah!
? Comb their hair and shine their shoes ?
? I don't want to grow up ?
? Stay around my old hometown ?
? I don't want to put no money down ?
? I don't want to get me a big old loan ?
? Work them fingers to the bone ?
? I don't want to float a broom ?
? Fall in love and get married, then boom ?
? How the hell did it get here so soon? ?
? Well, I don't want to grow up ?
犹太人听起来挺吓人的  是吧
Jews sound scary, huh?
我不觉得
Not to me.
要是被我遇上  我就这样杀了他们
If I met one, I'd kill it like that.
就像...这样
Like... that.
可你怎么分辨得出来
But how would you know if you saw one?
他们看起来跟我们一样
They could look just like us.
我会摸摸他们头上有没有犄角
I'd feel its head for horns.
而且他们有一股球芽甘蓝的味道
And they smell like brussels sprouts.
对  我忘了球芽甘蓝这茬了
Oh, yeah. I forgot about the brussels sprouts bit.
想象一下抓个犹太人献给希特勒
Imagine catching one and giving it to Hitler.
这样肯定能加入他的私人护卫队
That'd be a surefire way to get into his personal guards.
然后我就能跟他成为最好的朋友
Then we would become best friends.
我还以为我才是你最好的朋友
I thought I was your best friend.
约克  你是我第二好的朋友
Yorki, you're my second-best friend.
第一名的位置是留给元首的
First place is reserved for the Führer.
除非你就是希特勒  藏在一个小胖子的身体里
So, unless you're Hitler hiding in a fat, little boy's body...
换我的话  能当第二就很开心了
I'd be happy with second place.
我想我只是个住在小胖子身体里的小胖子
I guess I'm just a kid in a fat kid's body.
结案了
Case closed.
当你们站在敌人面前  必须要结束他的生命
When you stand before the enemy and have to end his life,
你们谁有这个胆子动手
which of you will have the stomach to do this?
很好
Good.
希特勒的军队里没有多余的位置
There is no room in Hitler's army
给那些缺乏勇气的人
for those that lack strength.
我们要的是坚强的勇士
We want hardened warriors.
是那些准备好了随意杀戮的人
Those that are prepared to kill at will.
你们能做到吗
Can you do this?
-能  -嗯
- Yes. - Ja.
乔纳斯
Johannes.
你能下杀手吗
Can you kill?
当然了  我喜欢杀戮
Of course. I love killing.
很好  过来
Good. Come here.
别怕  来
Don't be scared. Come on.
很好
Good.
杀了它
Kill it.
扭它的脖子  杀了它
Wring its neck and kill the rabbit.
还是说你怕了
Or are you scared?
我没怕  我只是...
I'm not scared. I... I just...
动手
Now.
用两手卡住它的脖子  然后用力一拧
Place both hands around its neck and then one hard twist.
它可能会尖叫  但我们可以一脚踢死它
He might scream, but we'll just use the boot to finish it off.
杀了它  杀了它
Kill. Kill.
Kill. Kill. Kill.
杀了它  杀了它
快跑  快
Come on, shoo.
好样的
Good shot.
你是个胆小鬼
You are a coward.
跟你爸一样
Just like your father.
他不是胆小鬼
He... He's not a coward.
-他正在意大利作战  -是吗
- He's fighting in Italy. - Really?
但已经两年没人收到过他的消息了
But no one has heard from him in two years.
他就是个胆小的逃兵
He is a deserting coward.
他怕了  你也一样
He's scared and so are you.
你就跟小兔子一样害怕
You're as scared as a little rabbit.
害怕的小兔子
Scared little rabbit.
也许我们也该拧断你的脖子
Maybe we should snap your neck, too?
小兔乔乔
Jojo the rabbit.
乔乔兔
Jojo Rabbit.
乔乔兔  乔乔兔
Jojo Rabbit. Jojo Rabbit.
可怜的乔乔  怎么了  小男子汉
Poor Jojo. What's wrong, little man?
-你好  阿道夫  -想跟我说说兔子的事吗
- Hi, Adolf. - Wanna tell me about that rabbit incident?
是怎么回事
What was all that about?
他们想让我杀了它
They wanted me to kill it.
抱歉  我没能做到
I'm sorry. I couldn't.
不用担心  我一点都不在意
Don't worry about it. I couldn't care less.
可他们现在管我叫害怕的小兔子
But now they call me a scared rabbit.
随他们怎么说吧
Let them say whatever they want.
人们也曾说过我很多难听的话
People used to say a lot of nasty things about me.
"这家伙是个疯子"
"Oh, this guy's a lunatic."
"瞧瞧那个疯子  他会把我们都害死"
"Oh, look at that psycho. He's gonna get us all killed."
我告诉你一个小秘密  兔子可不是胆小鬼
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret. The rabbit is no coward.
不起眼的小兔子每天都面对着一个危险的世界
The humble little bunny faces a dangerous world every day,
还要为自己的家人和祖国找胡萝卜
hunting carrots for his family, for his country.
我的帝国将容纳各种动物
My empire will be full of all animals.
狮子  长颈鹿  斑马
Lions, giraffes, zebras,
犀牛  章鱼
rhinoceroses, octopuses,
犀章鱼
rhinoctopuses.
甚至是非凡的兔子
Even the mighty rabbit.
来根烟吗
Cigarette?
不  谢谢  我不抽烟
Oh, no, thanks. I don't smoke.
我给你点真正有用的建议吧
Let me give you some really good advice.
就做兔子
Be the rabbit.
不起眼的小兔能智取它的所有敌人
The humble bunny can outwit all of his enemies.
它勇敢  悄无声息而又内心强大
He's brave and sneaky and strong.
就  做  兔子
Be the rabbit.
乔乔
Jojo!
你还好吗  乔乔
Are you all right, Jojo?
你在跟谁说话
Who were you talking to?
没谁
Nobody.
我还以为你在哭
Oh, I thought you were crying.
你是眼泪专家吗
Are you a teardrop specialist?
不是
No.
结案了
Case closed.
现在轮到乔乔让那些竹节虫看看
Now, it's time for Jojo to show those stick insects
谁才是真正胆小的兔子了
who is the real cowardly rabbit.
抱歉  你在说什么
I'm sorry, what are you talking about?
没什么
Never mind.
乔乔  你去哪
Jojo, where are you going?
去做兔子
To be the rabbit!
乔乔兔  乔乔兔  找萝卜  乔乔兔
Jojo Rabbit. Jojo Rabbit. Hunting carrots. Jojo Rabbit.
太棒了
Hey, this is amazing.
我们就像两头人类羚羊
We're like two human antelopes.
好了  小伙子们  你们每个人都将有机会
Now, lads, each of you will be given the opportunity
拉燃并投掷一枚手榴弹
to ignite and throw a grenade.
我将亲自下场监督
I will personally be supervising each of you
确保你们不会把自己的眼珠子炸出来
to make sure you don't blow your eyes out or something.
好了  谁先来
All right, who's first?
克劳斯
Klaus.
该死
Shit.
Shit!
别学他
Don't do that.
乔乔  乔乔
Jojo. Jojo.
芬克尔  芬克尔
Finkel! Finkel!
乔乔  乔乔
Jojo, Jojo.
我的天啊
O-M Gott.
他的脸像幅抽象画
He looks like a Picasso painting.
他妈妈会杀了我的
His mother's going to kill me.
我亲爱的崽崽
My darling cub.
小家伙
Hey, kid.
我亲爱的崽崽
My darling little cub.
你为什么这么高兴
Why so happy?
你儿子丑得像个怪物
Your son is ugly like a monster.
你才不是怪物
You're no monster.
而且你的疤会好的
Besides, your scars will heal,
你的腿能基本恢复原样
and you'll get most of the movement back in your leg.
但我再也当不了希特勒的私人警卫了
But I'll never be in Hitler's personal guards.
你这样挺好的
Ah, you're fine as you are.
你能回家我就很高兴了
I'm just happy to have you back home.
正好狮子爸爸又不在
Mama Lion worries about her cub,
狮子妈妈可担心她的崽崽了
especially when Papa Lion isn't here.
还有狮子英格
Or Inge Lion.
你把兔子尾巴围着耳朵绕一圈
You grab the rabbit by the tail, wrap it around his ear,
绑好以后塞回耳朵洞里
tie it all up and then stuff him back down the hole.
好啦  我们出发吧
Now then, let's get on our way, huh?
我觉得出去走走
I think getting out of the house will
对你的康复有好处
do wonders for your recuperation.
我不想出去
I don't want to go out there.
什么  别说傻话  你当然想出去
What? Don't be silly. Of course you do.
我看上去很蠢
I look stupid.
别人会盯着我看的
People will stare.
享受注目礼吧  孩子
Enjoy the attention, kid.
不是谁都有运气长得蠢
Not everyone's lucky enough to look stupid.
比如我就摆脱不了天生丽质的命运
I, for one, am cursed to look incredibly attractive.
现在你要鼓起勇气
Now, you're going to pluck up your courage,
走出家门来一场华丽冒险
walk out that door and have an incredible adventure.
好吗
Okay?
好
Okay.
陆军元帅乔乔  你是我们最厉害的战士
Field Marshal Jojo, you're our top man.
准备动身离开这栋房子
Prepare to leave the house.
这任务危险吗
Is it dangerous?
极其危险
Extremely.
-希特勒万岁  -老天啊
- Heil Hitler. - Oh, Jesus.
-你看上去不错  小子  -希特勒万岁
- Looking good, kid. - Heil Hitler!
贝茨勒夫人  您依旧如此迷人
Frau Betzler, you're looking fetching as usual.
好吧
Okay, wow.
我儿子走路一瘸一拐都是你的错
It's because of you my son can't walk properly
他脸上也乱七八糟的
and has a messed-up face.
他偷了我的手榴弹
He stole my hand grenade.
-他自己拿...  -知道了
- Just took it... - Ja, ja.
我上班的时候你会照顾他的  对吗
So, you are going to look after him while I'm at work, hmm?
保证他有事干  还是集体的一份子  懂了吗
Make sure he has a job and feels included. Got it?
懂了  完全明白
Got it. Ja, I really got it.
很好
Good.
伙计们  这位是乔纳斯·贝茨勒
Guys, this is Johannes Betzler.
我跟你们说过的
The kid I told you about.
记得吗  他偷了枚手榴弹
Remember, he stole a hand grenade
把自己炸上了天
and blew himself up and as a result
结果我因为玩忽职守降了级
I got demoted for negligence.
现在得在这间办公室和可爱的孩子们一起工作
Now I get to work in this office with all these wonderful kids.
乔乔  我们肯定能找点事给你干
So, Jojo. I'm sure we can figure out something for you to do.
谁有主意
Ideas?
-有  -谁有
- Ja. - Guys?
我有
Ja. Ja.
我们缺人帮忙遛下克隆体
Okay, well, we need somebody to walk the clones.
他还可以帮我们发下新传单
Also, I think maybe he could hand out this new propaganda,
满十岁即可加入希特勒青年团
追随我们的领袖
然后发个征兵通知
and deliver these conscriptions.
我会被征召入伍吗
I don't suppose I could be conscripted?
可以吗
Could I?
这可真是个好主意
Oh, yes, that's a wonderful idea.
我完全同意你
Yes, I give my full permission
送这位十岁的孩子上战场
for you to send this ten-year-old child into war.
有人能给他配把枪吗
Will someone get this kid a gun?
我非常乐意上前线
And I'd be more than happy to fight in the front.
排队去  小子
Get in line, kid.
好了  这是征兵通知
Okay. Here are the conscriptions,
这是枪
and here is a gun.
它有点...不要枪吗
It's a bit... for the gun?
不要
No.
我们有信心胜利
来为希特勒青年团效力
希特勒
社区和要塞要互相帮助
我们以忠于首领为荣
德国人民的战争条款
法肯海姆市
追随我们的领袖
我们欺骗了德国民众
恶心
Yuck.
看着
Look.
解放德国  反抗纳粹党
他们做了什么
What did they do?
他们能做的
What they could.
走吧
Come on.
喂  乔乔兔
Hey-hey! Jojo Rabbit!
瞧瞧你那张脸
Oh, look at your face.
我当兵啦  我要上战场啦
I am a soldier! I'm going to war!
你就是个邮差
And you are a postman!
乔乔兔  乔乔兔
Jojo Rabbit, Jojo Rabbit!
妈妈
Mama?
陆军元帅乔乔到家了
Field Marshal Jojo is home.
妈妈
Mama?
妈妈  我到家了
Mama? I'm home.
妈妈
Mama?
英格
你好
Hi.
你想干什么
What do you want?
你是鬼吗
Are you a ghost?
是啊  我是鬼
Sure. A ghost.
别逼我追你  小子
Don't make me run, kid.
我太饿了
I'm far too hungry
你知道我们有多喜欢血的滋味
and you know how much we love the taste of blood.
你在找什么
Lose something?
我不是鬼  乔纳斯  我比鬼还可怕
I'm not a ghost, Johannes. I'm something worse,
但你已经知道了  不是吗
but I think you already know that, don't you?
你知道我是什么
You know what I am.
-我不知道  -你知道
- No. - Yes.
说啊
Say it.
Say it!
犹太佬
A Jew.
祝福你
Gesundheit.
你不能留在这里
You can't be here.
是你妈妈邀请我来的
Well, your mother invited me,
所以我是她的客人
so I suppose that makes me her guest.
-这是禁止的  -你要怎么办  亲爱的小希特勒
- It's not allowed. - What will you do, sweet Hitlerchen?
当然了
Of course.
去吧  告诉他们
Go on, then. Tell them.
但你知道接下来会怎么样吗
But do you know what happens if you do?
我会告诉他们你帮了我
I'll tell them you helped me.
还有你妈妈
And your mother, too.
然后我们一起完蛋
Then we'll all be kaputt.
如果你敢和你妈妈说你发现我了  哪怕说一句
And if you tell her you know about me, just one word...
我就要给这世界做件大好事
I'll do the world a great, big favor
砍掉你的纳粹脑袋
and cut your Nazi head off.
明白了吗
Got it?
明白
Ja.
这个我就留下了  挺漂亮的
I think I'll hold onto this. It's pretty.
真刺激
That was intense.
-我要怎么办  -说实话  不知道
- What am I going to do? - Honestly, no idea.
可能不止她一个
I mean, there could be more of them.
几百个住在你家墙里的犹太人
Hundreds of them living in your walls.
她是怎么夺走主导权的
How did she get control like that?
她肯定用了她的魔力
She must've used her powers.
心灵控制
Mind control.
老一套了
Oh, typical.
-你看到她移动得多快了吗  -看到了
- Did you see how fast she moved? - Yes.
美国短跑与跳远名将
就像个幼小女性版本的杰西·欧文斯
Like a little, female Jewish Jesse Owens.
-现在她还拿走了你的好刀  -我的刀
- And now she's got your fancy knife. - My knife!
对  就像个幼小女性版本的杰西·欧文斯
Yeah. Like a little, female Jewish Jesse Owens,
开膛手杰克
Jack the Ripper.
你绝对有麻烦了
You're definitely in a pickle, my friend.
怎么办  怎么办
Ah, what to do, what to do?
-想到了  -想到了
- Got it! - Got it!
-谈判  -烧掉房子
- I will negotiate. - Burn down the house
然后怪罪温斯顿·丘吉尔
and blame Winston Churchill.
或者谈判
Or negotiate.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
小姑娘
Little girl?
墙里面的犹太姑娘
Jew girl in the wall?
喂  犹太佬
Yoo-hoo. Jew?
那好  我就直接说我要说的话吧
Okay, well, I'll just say what I have to say and that's this:
我不怕你
I'm not scared of you
并且我认为你应该换个地方住
and I think you should find somewhere else to live.
行吗
Okay?
不行
Not okay.
滚出我的房间
Get the hell out of my room.
她真粗鲁
She's pretty rude, you know?
这是我的个人意见
That's just my two Pfennige.
-而且她现在有两把刀了  -我知道
- And now she's got two knives. - I know!
-你要怎么切东西  -我不知道
- How are you going to chop up stuff? - I don't know!
而且她还在那上面
Oh, and she's still up there, too.
那个...那东西  那个...
That... that thing, that, that...
-犹太人  -对  犹太人
- Jew. - Yeah. Jew, yeah.
-我们要怎么对付那个犹太人  -想点办法
- What are we gonna do about that Jew? - You think of something.
现在我成专家了
Oh, now I'm the expert?
别再给我香烟了  我才十岁
Stop offering me damned cigarettes! I'm ten!
行  抱歉  我压力太大了
All right. Sorry. I'm stressed out!
好  我们直说吧
Okay, let's talk like turkeys.
你不能告诉你妈妈
You can't tell your mother
要不那个犹太人会砍掉你的纳粹脑袋
or that Jew will cut off your Nazi head,
但没理由让这个阁楼里的玩意
but there's no reason this thing in the attic needs
毁掉你的生活
to ruin your life.
实际上  你可以利用这一点
In fact, you could use it to your advantage.
怎么做
How?
别人企图对我使用心灵控制时
When someone tries to use mind powers on me,
你知道我怎么做吗
know what I do?
反过来对他们用心灵控制
Use mind powers back on them.
记得去年那个独臂海盗冯施陶芬伯格
Remember last year when that one-arm pirate von Stauffenberg
1944年以一枚临时组装的定时炸弹
刺杀希特勒的德国陆军上校
企图用一枚桌子下的炸弹炸死我的事吗
tried to blow me up with a table bomb?
对  你活下来了
Yeah, you survived.
更正
Correctomundo.
除了拥有防炸弹腿之外
The only reason I survived,
我幸存的唯一原因
apart from having bombproof legs,
就是我智取了老冯施陶
is because I outwitted old von Stauffy.
我让他以为我死了
I let him think that I was dead,
但实际上  我安然无恙
when in actual fact, I was absolutely fine.
通过装死  我引出了所有叛徒
By pretending I was dead, I drew out all the traitors.
所以你要怎么做
So what are you going to do?
装死
Pretend I'm dead?
正是  等等  不
Exactly. Wait, no.
不  我的意思是
No, what I mean is this:
给她制造安全感  然后她会卸下防备
make her feel safe and then she'll drop her guard
然后你就取得主导权了
and then you will be the one in control.
-反向心理  -别把事情复杂化
- Reverse psychology. - Don't complicate things.
就用我的反向心灵控制招数
Just use my backwards mind power trick,
然后一切都会解决的
and everything will be fine.
我得走了
I gotta go.
今晚我那边晚餐要吃独角兽
We're having unicorn for dinner at my place tonight.
专心  乔乔
Concentrate, Jojo.
记住  一个犹太人生活在你家墙里
Remember, a Jew living in your wall
好过两个犹太人扑闪着蝙蝠翅膀飞在外面
is better than two Jews flying around with their bat wings
沿着烟囱爬下来吃掉无辜的纳粹
climbing down chimneys and eating innocent Nazis.
还有别再给她刀了
And don't give her any more knives.
再见
Tschüss.
亲爱的崽崽  你怎么没睡
Darling cub, why are you up, huh?
你吃过东西了吗
Did you eat anything, hmm?
抱歉  我忘了时间
Sorry, I lost track of time.
我去散步了  然后...
I was taking a long walk and having a thing...
我们该拿你的鞋带怎么办  老天
What are we going to do with these laces, huh? My goodness.
你总会学会系鞋带的  是不是
You'll learn how to tie them eventually, no?
-我听到她的声音了  -什么
- I heard her. - What?
谁
Who?
英格
Inge.
她的鬼魂
Her ghost.
你真惨
That's so sad for you.
你发疯了
You've lost your mind.
然而我更惨
It's sadder for me, though,
因为我得和一个疯子住一起
because I have to live with a crazy person.
我听到有动静  在楼上
I heard noises. Upstairs.
鬼魂  说真的  你知道我听到了什么动静吗  老鼠
Ghosts? Honestly. You know what I heard? Rats.
对  我们家里有老鼠  你能相信吗
Yes, we have them. Can you believe that?
肮脏的动物
Dirty animals.
我一直想叮嘱你不要上楼
I've been meaning to tell you to stay away from upstairs,
直到我把老鼠清理干净  好吗
until I've cleared them all, okay?
我不想让你生病
I don't need you getting sick.
好  妈妈
Okay, Mama.
我会警惕那些肮脏的老鼠
I'll watch out for those dirty rats.
刀都去哪了
Where are all the goddamn knives?
你也要上床睡觉了吗
Are you going to bed, too?
对  马上
Yes. Soon.
我得先整理一些东西
I have to tidy some things first.
什么东西
What things?
妈妈的东西
Mama things.
小子  你得信任我  好吗
Boy, you have to trust me, okay?
我是家里的老大  是不是
I'm the boss here, ja?
我猜是吧
I guess.
好孩子
Good boy.
对  但用一只眼  像这样
Yes, but with... with one eye. Like...
很接近了
Almost.
不太对
Not quite.
很棒  你学会了
Great. You got it.
好
Ja.
你得再安静点
You have to be more quiet.
他听到了楼上有动静
He heard noises up here.
如果我要在你和我儿子之间做选择  我...
If I have to choose between you and my son, I...
我都不知道该把你送到哪里去
I won't know where to send you.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
他不能知道  他知道的话  他们也会知道
He can't know. If he knows, then they know.
-你可以跟他讲道理  -你不了解他
- You could reason with him. - You don't know him.
他是个狂热分子
He's a fanatic.
他花了三周才接受了
It took him three weeks to get over the fact
他祖父不是金发的事实
that his grandfather was not blond.
我知道那个小男孩就在他内心某处
I know he's in there somewhere.
那个喜欢玩耍  因为害怕雷声
The little boy who loves to play and runs to you
而奔向你的小男孩
because he's scared of thunder.
以为你发明了巧克力蛋糕的小男孩
Thinks you invented chocolate cake.
到头来  这是你仅有的东西
In the end, that's all you have.
希望
Hope...
你仅剩的孩子不是又一个鬼魂
that your only remaining child is not just another ghost.
或许我们现在都是鬼魂  只是自己不知道
Perhaps we're all ghosts now. We just don't know it.
或许吧
Perhaps.
你比大多数人都活得久
You've lived more lifetimes than most.
我根本就没活过
I haven't lived at all.
你受到了挑战
You're being challenged.
他们说你不能活着  你活不下去
They say you can't live, that you won't live.
如果成真了  那他们就赢了
If that comes true, then they win.
他们至今一直都在赢
They've been winning so far.
他们永远都不会赢  这就是你身上的力量
They'll never win. That's the power you have.
只要有人活在某个地方  那他们就输了
As long as there's someone alive, somewhere, then they lose.
他们昨天或今天都没抓到你
They didn't get you yesterday or today.
那你明天也要一样活着
You make tomorrow the same.
明天一定是一样的
Tomorrow must be the same.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ!
你必须拉伸
You must stretch.
弄疼你了吗
Does that hurt you?
-是的  -很好  痛苦就是你的朋友
- Yes. - Good. Pain is your friend.
很快你的腿就会
Soon your leg will only be
只有一点畸形  并不碍事
a little bit deformed and pointless.
但我还要建议你休学一个月
I'm going to recommend another month off school though
因为你的脸可能会吓到别的孩子
because your face might scare the other kids.
有点丑
It's kind of ugly.
好了  下一个是谁
Okay, who's next?
乔乔
Jojo.
宝贝  我得走了
Baby, I have to go.
我们家里见
I'll see you at home.
-你好  克上尉  -你好
- Hi, Captain K. - Hey.
这不是手榴弹先生吗
If it isn't Herr Hand Grenade himself.
腿怎么样了  小子
How's the leg, kid?
愈合得差不多了
It's pretty much healed.
疼痛降到80%了
It only 80% hurts now.
你们在做什么
What are you guys doing?
我来给希特勒青年团
I'm being made to teach the HJ boys
做水战培训
water warfare training.
以防他们需要
You know, in case they ever need
在游泳池里作战
to go to battle in a swimming pool.
我能问你一个关于犹太人的问题吗
Can I ask you a question about Jews?
天啊  为什么
Oh, God. Why?
我要是看到了一个该怎么办
What should I do if I see one?
好吧
Okay.
如果你看到了犹太人  告诉我们
If you see a Jew, you tell us,
我们告诉盖世太保  他们会告诉保卫军
we tell the Gestapo, and they tell the SS,
然后他们会去杀了那个犹太人
and then they go and they kill the Jew.
以及帮助了那个犹太人的所有人
And anyone who helped the Jew.
因为现在是个多疑的时期
And because these are very paranoid times,
保险起见  可能还会多杀几个人
probably some other people just in case.
流程很冗长
It's a pretty drawn out process.
即使那个犹太人一开始就催眠了别人
Even if the Jew hypnotized someone
让对方藏起了自己吗
to make them hide the Jew in the first place?
要是真有此事  我肯定会惊呆的
I'd be amazed if that could happen.
不  有可能的
No, it can happen.
我叔叔就是这样
It happened to my uncle.
一个犹太人催眠了他
A Jew hypnotized him
然后他成为了一个酒鬼以及赌鬼
and he became a massive drunk and a gambler.
他还背叛了自己的妻子
And he cheated on his wife
和我妹妹有不正当关系
and he had an inappropriate relationship with my sister.
然后他在一场无关的事故中淹死了
And then he drowned in an unrelated accident,
但都是因为那个犹太人
but it was the Jew's fault.
总之  你看到犹太人了吗
Anyway. Did you see one? A Jew.
我不确定我能不能分辨出来
I'm not sure I'd be able to tell if I did.
嗯  我也不能
Yeah, me neither.
摘掉他们可笑帽子  根本分辨不出
Without their funny hats, it's damn near impossible.
应该有人写本关于这个主题的书
Someone should write a book on the subject.
能让我们省心许多
It would make things so much easier.
-肯定会大卖  -是
- It would be a hit. - Ja.
芬克尔  他们要溺水了  走吧
Finkie, they're drowning. Come on.
回见  小伙子
I'll see you later, little man.
好了  情况是这样的
Okay, here's the situation.
如果我去告发你  你会有大麻烦
If I tell on you, you'll be in big trouble,
我看你也不愿意
and I don't think you want that.
但之后你会告发我和我母亲
But then you'll tell on me and my mother,
我们就会有麻烦
and we'll be in trouble,
这个我也不愿意
which I don't want.
如果你告诉我妈妈我知道了  那她会赶你出去
And if you tell my mother I know, then she'll kick you out,
这个你也不愿意
which you don't want.
如果我告诉我妈妈我知道了
And if I tell my mother I know,
那你就会把我的纳粹脑袋砍下来
then you'll cut off my Nazi head,
这个我也不愿意
which I also don't want.
所以这就是一场墨西哥僵局
So, it's a Mexican stalemate.
只是普通的僵局
It's just a normal stalemate.
我有几个条件  可以允许你留下来
I have some conditions for allowing you to stay here.
-"条件"  -是的
- "Conditions?" - Yes.
告诉我所有犹太种族的事情
Tell me everything about the Jewish race.
好的
Okay.
我们和你们相似
We're like you,
但我们是人类
but human.
请认真对待
Please take this seriously.
把这个当作揭秘吧
Think of this as an exposé.
我想知道你们所有的秘密
I want to know all your secrets.
请不要坐在我姐姐的床上
Kindly refrain from sitting on my sister's bed.
为什么  她又不需要了
Why? She doesn't need it.
你对我姐姐一无所知
You know nothing of my sister.
英格和我是朋友
Inge and I were friends.
我记得你
I remember you.
奇怪的小男孩
Such a funny little boy.
寒暄结束
Enough with the small talk.
快跟我说说你们的种族
Start telling me about your kind.
显然  我们是爱钱如命的魔鬼
Obviously, we are demons who love money.
对吧
Right?
显然是的  大家都知道
Obviously. Everyone knows that.
但人们不知道我们也对食物过敏
But what people don't know is that we're also allergic to food.
奶酪  面包  肉
Cheese, bread, meat.
只要一口就能要我们的命
That stuff will kill us instantly.
所以你如果想了结我的性命
So, if you're thinking of ending my life,
这是最快的办法
that's the fastest way.
还有饼干  很致命
Also biscuits, lethal.
很幽默
Very funny.
总之  没有你的食物
Anyway, there's not enough food for you,
所以我不知道你该怎么办
so I don't know what you're going to do.
你妈妈给我找了一些面包
Your mother managed to find me some bread.
她很善良  把我当人对待
She's kind. She treats me like a person.
但你不是  不是正经的人
But you're not. Not a proper person.
你是吗
Are you?
你好大的胆子  犹太佬
How dare you, Jew!
你像一根睫毛一样脆弱
You are weak like an eyelash.
我是雅利安的后人
I am born of Aryan ancestry.
我的鲜血是纯正的红玫瑰的颜色
My blood is the color of a pure red rose.
我的眼睛湛蓝如...
And my eyes are blue like...
挣脱啊
Break free.
挣脱啊  伟大的雅利安人  犹太人都不脆弱
Break free, great Aryan. There are no weak Jews.
我的祖先与天使摔跤  与巨人厮杀
I am descended from those who wrestle angels and kill giants.
我们是神选之子
We were chosen by God.
你们却是被一个胡子都长不全的
You were chosen by a pathetic little man
可悲小矮子选出来的
who can't even grow a full mustache.
更强大的种族吗
The stronger race, huh?
楼上的那个犹太人进展如何了
So, how's it all going with that Jew thing upstairs?
她不想和我谈
Well, she doesn't want to talk to me.
嗯  毕竟你是个纳粹
Mm-hmm. Well, you are a Nazi.
有道理
I guess.
这本书会比我想的更难写
This book is going to be harder to write than I thought.
她在做什么  她在烧东西
What's she doing? She's burning something.
她在烧什么
What is she burning?
-你在烧什么  -她听不到你的声音
- What are you burning? - She can't hear you.
你在烧什么
What are you burning?
你乐呵什么
Why so happy?
局势变了
Things are changing.
同盟国拿下了意大利
The Allies have taken Italy.
下一个就是法国  马上战争就要结束了
France will be next and soon the war will be over.
该死的  那你有什么可高兴的
Goddamn it! Why does that make you happy?
你就这么恨你的祖国吗
You hate your country that much?
我爱我的祖国  我恨的是战争
I love my country. It's the war I hate.
毫无意义且愚蠢至极
It's pointless and stupid,
我们越早恢复和平越好
and the sooner we have peace, the better.
战争肯定会结束
Oh, the war will end.
我们会把敌人碾为尘埃
We will crush our enemies into dust.
等他们都被消灭了
And when they are destroyed,
我们就要用他们的坟墓当厕所
we shall use their graves as toilets.
好了  不谈政治了
Okay. No more politics.
晚餐是中立地带  这张餐桌就是瑞士
Dinner is neutral ground. This table is Switzerland.
吃吧
Let's eat.
你怎么不吃
You aren't eating.
我不是很饿
No. I am not that hungry.
过会儿再吃
I might eat later.
现在嚼嚼这葡萄就挺好
For now, I am just going to chew on these grapes.
我今晚可是饿坏了
Well, I'm especially hungry tonight.
要不我把你那份也吃了吧
So maybe I'll just finish yours.
浪费不太好
Don't want it to go to waste.
今天过得怎么样  乔纳斯
How was your day, Johannes?
还不就是四处游荡
Oh, you know, just wandered around,
当一个生无可恋的畸形小孩
being a deformed kid with nothing to live for.
你才不是畸形
You're not deformed.
我的脸都成一张街道地图了  女人
My face looks like a goddamn street map, woman.
没指望你能懂
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
要是我爸爸在这  他肯定会懂我
If my father were here, he'd get it.
问题是他不在
Well, he's not.
我知道  所以我只能跟你困在一起
I know. And instead, I'm stuck with you.
你想见你爸
You want your dad, 'eh?
是的  我想
Yeah, I do.
-是吗  真的吗  -是  真的
- Yeah? Yeah? - Yeah. Yeah.
-确定吗  -确定
- Yeah? - Yeah!
行
Fine.
不准用这种口气跟你娘说话
Don't you ever talk to your goddamn mother like that!
保罗  怎么了
Paul, what happened?
保罗
Paul?
我吼孩子了
I yelled at the kid.
什么  去跟他道歉
What? Go apologize.
抱歉  孩子
Sorry, kid.
什么
What?
你这算什么道歉
What kind of apology was that?
对不起  孩子
Sorry, kid.
乔乔
Jojo...
我知道你想我  但是...
I know you miss me, but I'm...
我正在外面奋战试图改变这个世界
I'm out there trying to make a difference in the world.
我不在的日子里
And while I'm gone,
我需要你照顾好我的罗茜
I need you to take care of my Rosie.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
能  爸爸
Yes, Dad.
谢谢
Thanks.
她也在尽她所能
She's doing what she can.
天呐  我们真是生了个乖孩子
Oh, gosh. We made a good kid, huh?
真好喝
Damn, that's good.
让我想起了和罗茜在红色沙龙跳舞的日子
It reminds me of dancing with Rosie in The Red Salon.
你还记得吗  亲爱的
You remember, honey?
当然记得  老公
Of course I do, babe.
别光坐着  孩子
Hey, don't just sit there, kid.
过来
Come.
跟你爸妈一起跳舞  来
Dance with your parents, come.
我需要你画一张犹太人的生活地点图
So, I'd like you to draw a picture of where Jews live.
你们在哪里吃饭睡觉
Where you all eat, sleep,
还有犹太蜂后在哪里产卵
and where the queen Jew lays the eggs.
你还真是个傻子
You really are an idiot.
动作快点  我们的任务繁重
Come on. We have a lot of work to do.
跟我说说你的家人
Tell me about your family.
我可以告诉你犹太人的情况
I'll tell you about the Jews,
但你无权了解我的家人
but you are not privileged to know about my family.
但是我需要背景资料
But I need background.
你为什么要找我玩
Why are you hanging around with me?
你是没朋友吗
Don't you have any friends?
当然有  约克
Of course. Yorki.
-约克  -他只是其中一个
- "Yorki?" - Amongst others.
但你一个朋友都没有
Well, you don't have anyone.
我有内森
I have Nathan.
内森  他是什么人
"Nathan?" Who the hell is that?
-我的未婚夫  我有他  -他人在哪
- My fiancé. I have him. - Where is he?
在反纳粹组织里战斗  看
Fighting in the resistance, see.
他在小河边向我求的婚
He proposed to me on the banks of the Fluss.
像谦谦君子一样单膝跪地
He knelt down like a proper gentleman,
念了一首里尔克的诗
recited a poem by Rilke.
我答应了他  一起跳舞到夜幕来临
And when I said yes, we danced into the night.
真无聊
Snore.
里尔克是谁
Who's Rilke?
一位伟大诗人  内森的最爱
A great poet. Nathan's favorite.
内森的最爱是吗
Oh, Nathan's favorite? Yay.
他会来救我  然后我们去巴黎定居
He's coming to rescue me, then we'll go live in Paris.
你要永远背叛德国吗
You'd turn your back on Germany forever?
是德国先背叛的我
It turned on me first.
反正我们也不需要你
Well, we don't need you.
你和你的傻子男友就闭上嘴巴
You and your stupid boyfriend can shut up
住到那个该死的奶酪蜗牛长棍面包之地去吧
and go live in damn cheese, snail, baguette land.
你这是因为没有女友说的气话
Now, now, just because you don't have a girlfriend.
我是忙得没空交女友
I'm way too busy for a girlfriend.
总有一天你会腾出时间的
One day, you'll make time.
到时候你的心里会只有她
You'll think of nothing else.
你会遇到你的心上人  每天都渴望着
You'll meet someone and spend your days
能再次将她拥入怀抱的那一刻
dreaming of the moment you can hold them in your arms again.
那就是爱
That's love.
-胡说八道  -画完了
- Ridiculous. - Finished.
傻瓜
我是要你画犹太人住的地方
I said to draw where Jews live.
这是我脑袋的破画像
This is just a stupid picture of my head.
没错  我们就住那儿
Yeah. That's where we live.
里尔克  里尔克  里尔克
Rilke, Rilke, Rilke.
你在哪儿呢  写诗的笨蛋
Where are you? Poetry-writing dumbhead.
赖内·马利亚·里尔克
真是个好主意  小兔子
Yes. Great thinking, Rabbit.
我们就用这些书
We'll use all of these books
铺一块假地板  好让她踩空掉下去
to make a fake floor that she'll fall through.
跌进满是食人鱼  岩浆和培根肉的坑里
Straight into a pit full of piranhas and... and lava and bacon.
她都不知道自己是怎么死的
Why, she won't know what hit her.
你安静  还管我
You shush. Shush me?
赶紧拿本书走吧  图书馆什么的最蠢了
Let's get a book and let's go. Libraries are dumb.
是为了学会放手
我们现在做的事真是太绝妙了
Yeah, this is a really good idea, what we're doing right now.
她要是有心  这么做能把她的心劈成两半
If she had a heart, this would break it clean in two.
我有事要告诉你
I have something to tell you.
我无意中发现了一封内森以前寄的信
I came across an old letter from Nathan,
你的未婚夫  写给你的
your fiancé, addressed to you.
-你在说什么呢  -我直接念吧
- What the hell are you talking about? - I'll just read it.
亲爱的爱莎  虽然很难以启齿
"Dear Elsa, this is hard for me to say,
但我不想娶你了
but I don't want to marry you anymore.
我找到了新爱人  我们经常大笑
I found a new woman and we laugh a lot
还会舌吻
and do the tongue-kiss.
就像我最喜爱的诗人里尔克说的
It's like my favorite poet, Rilke, says,
"我们之所以相爱  是为了学会
'We need in love to practice only this:
放手彼此"
letting each other go.'
所以再见了  抱歉我放手让你走
So, goodbye and sorry about letting you go.
你的前未婚夫  内森
From Nathan, your ex-fiancé.
又及  我没有参加反纳粹组织
"PS, I'm not really in the resistance.
我撒谎了
"I was lying.
我现在没有工作  而且变得很胖
I'm unemployed and quite fat now."
不用开门
Don't open the door,
我刚刚忘了还有另外一封信
but I actually forgot there was a second letter.
亲爱的爱莎
"Dear Elsa...
我想让你知道
I just wanted to let you know that
我现在不想与你分手了
I don't want to break up with you now.
我改变主意了
I changed my mind
因为我不想看到你为了我而自杀
because I don't want you to kill yourself over me,
过去有好几个姑娘这样做了
which a couple of girls have done in the past,
搞得我压力很大
and it's pretty stressful.
我要你好好活着
I need you to stay alive.
谢天谢地有那孩子照顾你
Thank God you're being taken care of by that kid
不得不说他真的是少年英杰
who I must say is a remarkable young man beyond his years.
也很勇敢
And brave, too.
等时机成熟我们就结婚
And let's still get married sometime,
虽然我现在真的没有工作
even though I am truly unemployed
也没忙什么正事
and have nothing going on for me.
你的  内森
Yours, Nathan."
-贝多芬  -爱因斯坦
- Beethoven. - Einstein.
-巴赫  -格什温
- Bach. - Gershwin.
勃拉姆斯  瓦格纳  莫扎特
Brahms. Wagner. Mozart.
你只知道音乐家吗
Musicians, is that all you have?
里尔克
Rilke.
当然有他
Oh, yeah, of course.
你最爱的里尔克  他妈妈是犹太人
Your favorite, Rilke. Jewish mother.
那就黛德丽
Dietrich, then.
胡迪尼
Houdini.
-不  不可能吧  -相信我  兄弟
- No. That's impossible. - Believe it, brother.
不信去问毕沙罗  莫迪利亚尼  曼雷  斯坦因
Just ask Pissarro, Modigliani, Man Ray, Gertrude Stein,
摩西甚至是救世主本人耶稣基督  阿门
Mr. Moses and the king of them all, Jesus Christi. Amen.
你只是胡说古代的人名罢了
Well, you're just saying any old name now.
这些人我都没听说过  我不玩了
I've never heard of these people and now I'm fed up.
如果你又找到内森的信
If you find any more of those letters,
可以告诉我吗
will you let me know?
可以
Sure.
好的
Okay.
再见
Bye.
河岸上以前有很多恋人约会
Ah, these banks used to be full of lovers.
在这唱歌跳舞
There was dancing and singing.
很浪漫
Romance.
现在可没时间搞浪漫
There's no time for romance.
我们身处战争中
We're at war.
总是有时间搞浪漫的
There's always time for romance.
总有一天你会遇到对的人
Someday you'll meet someone special.
为什么大家都这么跟我说
Why does everyone keep telling me that?
还有谁跟你说过
Who else tells you that?
大家
Everyone.
反正
Anyway.
是个愚蠢的想法
It's a stupid idea.
你才愚蠢
You're stupid.
爱是世界上最强大的东西
Love is the strongest thing in the world.
我想你会发现
I think you'll find that
金属才是世界上最强大的东西
metal is the strongest thing in the world.
紧随其后的是炸药  然后是肌肉
Followed closely by dynamite, and then muscles.
再说了  就算见到爱情我也认不出
Besides, I wouldn't even know it if I saw it.
毫不意外
Surprise, surprise.
你的鞋带又开了
Your shoelaces are undone again.
乔乔
Oh, Jojo.
等你遇到爱情  你会知道的
You'll know when it happens.
你会感受到
You'll feel it.
爱是疼痛
It's a pain.
-我赌是屁股疼  -是肚子疼
- In my arse, I bet. - In your tummy.
就像吃了一大堆蝴蝶一样
Like, like, you're full of butterflies.
-恶心  -是很恶心
- Yuck. - Yeah, "yuck."
好了  屎特勒  我们走吧
Come on, Shitler. Let's get a move on.
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
你这样我好担心啊  你又喝多了吗
I'm worried about you, man. Are you drunk? Again?
来吧  天啊
Come on. Oh, God.
能帮我解开吗
Could you please untie them?
-你真是长胖了  -我才没有
- You're really getting fat. - I'm not...
要不我把你扔在这吧  行吗
You know what? Why don't I just leave you here, okay?
-不行  -我明天再来找你
- No. - I'll come and get you tomorrow.
-可以吗  -不  妈妈妈妈
- Okay? How about that? - No. Mama, Mama!
你自己能行的  宝贝
You'll figure it out, darling.
-不行  -我回家等你
- No! - I'll meet you back at the house.
-我们明天见  -妈妈妈妈
- I'll see you tomorrow morning. - Mama, Mama!
你长大的速度太快了
You're growing up too fast.
十岁小孩不应该歌颂战争  讨论政治
Ten-year-olds shouldn't be celebrating war and talking politics.
你应该去爬树
You should be climbing trees
然后从树上摔下来
and then falling out of those trees.
但是元首说等我们打赢了
But the Führer says when we win
就轮到我们这些小男孩统治世界了
it is us, young boys who will rule the world.
帝国正在走向灭亡
The Reich is dying.
我们会战败
We're going to lose the war
到那时你怎么办
and then what are you going to do, hmm?
生命是恩赐
Life is a gift.
我们要歌颂生命
We must celebrate it.
要用舞蹈来告诉上帝我们感激生而为人
We have to dance to show God we are grateful to be alive.
我可不跳
Well, I won't dance.
跳舞是没工作的人才会干的事
Dancing is for people who don't have a job.
跳舞是自由的人会干的事
Dancing is for people who are free.
是逃离残酷现实的解药
It's an escape from all this.
那你一路跳着舞回家吧
Well, you're free to dance your way home.
我骑车
I'll ride.
你想得美
Oh, no, you don't.
没人能阻止我
No one can stop me.
欢迎回家  小伙子们
Welcome home, boys!
回家去亲吻妈妈吧
Now, go home and kiss your mothers!
恐怕今天没有内森的消息
No news from Nathan today, I'm afraid.
他可能在处理要事
He's probably doing something amazing,
忙着读书或者忙着长胡子
like reading a book or growing a beard.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我给你讲讲犹太人吧
You want me to tell you about the Jews?
随便
Don't care.
最开始我们是住在山洞里的
In the beginning, we used to live in caves.
-在地心深处  -等等
- Deep, deep in the center of the Earth. - Wait.
那可怕的地方住满了古怪奇妙的生物
Scary places full of strange and wonderful creatures
它们都有一个共同点
all with one thing in common.
喜欢收集包皮吗
Stealing the ends of penises?
不  你这白痴
No, you idiot.
-是对艺术的热爱  -不是割包皮吗
- The love of art. - No cutting penises off?
你还听不听故事了
Do you want the story or not?
你继续说吧  但是我知道那是真的
You may continue, but I know it's true.
割包皮那事
The penis thing.
拉比用那东西做耳塞
Rabbis use them for earplugs.
我继续说
And moving on.
在研究了多年魔法与咒语之后
After many years of developing magic and spells,
我们逐渐搬出了山洞  住进了城镇
we slowly moved out of the caves and into the towns.
有些人以动物的形态留在了山洞里
Some of us stayed in the caves, though, in animal bodies.
长成一坨坨的吗
Which are blobs or something?
我画出来给你看
Well, I'll draw them for you.
给
There.
上色的话会更好看
It'd be better with color.
犄角在哪
Where's the horns?
藏在头发里
Under the hair.
你的犄角呢
Where's yours?
我还年轻
I'm too young.
到二十一岁才开始长
They grow when you turn 21.
如今我们和普通人类生活在一起
These days we live among normal people,
但我们会经常强占民居
but often we take over a house
睡觉时倒挂在天花板上
and hang from the ceiling when we sleep.
像蝙蝠一样
Like bats.
读心者
还有
Oh, and another thing is
我们会读心术
we can read each other's minds.
我的天
Oh, my God.
谁的想法都能读吗
Everyone's minds?
-德国人的想法可以吗  -不行
- What about German minds? - No.
他们脑袋太厚  我们无法穿透
Their heads are too thick for us to penetrate.
和鸟类一样  我们的母语听起来就像唱歌
Like birds, our true language sounds like singing.
我们也喜欢亮闪闪的东西
And we're also attracted to shiny things.
水晶  玻璃  还有黄金
Crystals, glass and gold.
"喜欢亮闪闪的东西"
"Attracted to shiny things."
但也喜欢丑陋的东西
But also ugly things.
犹太人喜欢丑陋
Jews love ugliness.
这是我们在学校学到的
That's another thing we learned at school.
你们喜欢  对吧
You love them, yes?
丑陋的东西
Ugly things.
你们似乎相处得不错
You two seem to be getting on well.
我只是去看看她是不是还活着
I was just making sure she was still alive.
-你为什么要在乎  -我不在乎
- What do you care? - I don't.
我只是不想家里有个死人
I just don't want a dead person in my house.
-你想吗  -乐意之至
- How would you like it? - I'd love it.
请给我家多来点死人吧
More dead people in my house, please.
你们每天在一起这么长时间
Look, just all the time you two are spending together,
让我很不爽
it's making me feel very uncomfortable.
最初是你提议的
You suggested it in the first place.
是吗
Did I?
-是  -好吧  是我
- Yeah. - Oh, yeah, I did.
再说了  我是为了写书
Besides, it's for the book.
天  你说得有道理
Oh, God, you're right.
抱歉  我是不是说错话了
I'm sorry. Did I make it weird?
现在有点尴尬  是不是
It's weird now, isn't it?
我们之间不该这么尴尬
It shouldn't be weird between us.
这事不该尴尬
None of this should be weird.
没事  我只是累了  我要睡了
It's fine. I'm just tired. I'm going to bed.
好  我刚刚一直在帮你暖床
Ja, I was just keeping your bed warm for you.
真正的朋友就该这样
'Cause that's what real friends do.
你觉得我这身制服怎么样
Hey, what do think about this uniform?
大腿这里我拿不准
I'm not sure about the hips on the pants.
是不是应该再宽点儿
Should they be bigger?
-你很帅  -谢谢
- You look great. - Thank you.
乔乔  我能给你一条忠告吗
Now, listen, Jojo. Can I give you some really good advice?
你了解了她脑中的想法
When you see what's in her mind
你知道她想进入你脑中控制你
and where she's trying to make you go in your mind,
所以你一定要反其道而行之
in your mind, you must go the other way.
明白了吗
Get what I'm saying?
别让她禁锢你的想法
Do not let her put you in a brain prison.
亲爱的乔乔
That, dear Jojo,
那是绝对不可能  也不可以
is one thing that cannot and must not ever,
发生在德国人身上的
ever happen to a German!
不能让别人支配你的德国大脑
Do not let your German brain be bossed around!
我不会让她支配我的德国大脑  元首
I won't let her boss my German brain around, mein Führer.
尽你所能
Try not to.
你的书里已经收集了很多有用的信息了
Now, I think you've got a lot of good information in your book.
是时候让世人品鉴了  你说呢
It's time to show it to the world, don't you think?
没错
Ja.
阿道夫
Adolf?
你觉得我丑陋吗
Do you think I'm ugly?
当然
Yes.
他睡着了吗
Is he asleep?
他变了
He's different.
他起疑心了  认为英格的鬼魂住在这里
He suspects something. He thinks Inge's ghost lives up here.
你让我想起了她  真的
You remind me of her. You really do.
我多想看着她长大成为女人
I would love to have seen her grow into a woman.
但我只能看着你了
But I'll have to watch you instead.
我不知道什么叫成为女人
I don't know anything about being a woman.
这就是吗
Is that what it is?
喝酒什么的
You do things like drink wine?
当然了  要喝酒
Sure. You drink.
开心了喝香槟
Champagne, if you're happy.
难过了喝香槟
Champagne, if you're sad.
开车
You drive a car.
可以赌博
Gamble if you want.
买钻石
Own diamonds.
学着开枪
Learn how to fire a gun.
去摩洛哥旅行
You travel to Morocco.
找情人
Take up lovers.
让他们为情所困
Make them suffer.
你直视猛虎
You look a tiger in the eye.
然后毫无保留地信任
And trust without fear.
这就是成为女人的必经之路
That's what it is to be a woman.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do that?
你怎么知道可以信任一个人
How do you know you can trust someone?
信任就是了
You trust them.
晚安
Good night.
那些事情
All those other things.
你都做过吗
Did you do that stuff?
去摩洛哥  还有其他的
You know, go to Morocco and the rest?
没有
No.
我从未直视过猛虎
I never looked a tiger in the eye.
芬克尔  我说我们遇袭时需要德牧的意思
Finkel, I meant we'd need dogs for when the city is attacked,
是需要牧羊犬  而不是牧羊人
not actual German shepherds.
把他们带走
Get them out of here.
Get them out of here!
-现在就走  -请这边走
- Now! Now! Now! - Move along, please. Move along, please.
谢谢配合
Thank you, thank you.
-抱歉对你大喊大叫  -我好蠢
- I'm sorry for yelling at you. - I feel so stupid.
不不  是狗的名字太蠢  我应该说清楚的
No, no. It's a silly name for a dog. I should've been more clear.
-你做得很好  -谢谢
- You're doing a great job. - Danke.
你好  孩子
Hiya, kid.
今天有什么吩咐吗  贝茨勒长官
How can we help you today, Master Betzler?
什么事  跟我来吧
What's up? Walk with me.
揭发犹太人会有奖章什么的吗
If someone turned in a Jew, would they get a medal or something?
又是犹太人  你还对他们念念不忘吗
Jews, Jews, Jews. You're still going on about those people?
你知道我在为即将到来的敌军入侵做准备吧
You know I'm preparing the city for imminent invasion, right?
我在制定防御策略
I'm trying to plan a defense strategy.
西边是美国人
I've got Americans to the west,
东边是俄国人
got Russians to the east.
我朋友上次遇见了俄国人  被他们吃掉了
My friend once met some Russians and they ate him.
核桃是哪国人
Who's the walnuts?
核桃只是核桃  孩子
Walnuts are just walnuts, kid.
你想说什么来着
What do you want to talk about?
我学习了很多关于犹太人的知识
Well, I am learning a lot about Jews.
你们知道犹太人会读心术吗
Did you know Jews can read each other's minds?
还有他们睡觉时像蝙蝠一样倒挂着
And when they sleep, they hang from the ceiling, like bats.
真奇妙  你是怎么知道这些的
That's fascinating. And where did you come by this information?
研究得来的  我在写书
Research. I'm writing a book.
恭喜你  书名叫什么
Congratulations. What's it called?
《喂  犹太佬》
Yoohoo Jew.
是揭秘犹太人的
It's an exposé on Jews.
别名可以叫《犹太佬  你是谁》
You could also call it Who Are You, Jew?
《犹太新闻》怎么样
Or what about Jews News?
你还真是想象力丰富
Oh, you do have a wonderful imagination on you.
-我说的是真的  -当然是真的
- But it's real. - Ja, of course it's real.
我和你一样大时有个幻想好友叫康尼
When I was your age, I had an imaginary friend called Conny.
总是在我睡着的时候尿湿我的床
He used to wet my bed when I was asleep.
给我惹了很多麻烦
He got me in so much trouble.
过来  给你看看我在忙什么
Hey, come here. You might like to check out what I'm working on.
为了应对敌军入侵
As part of our preparations for the invasion,
我重新设计了制服
I'm redesigning my uniform.
注意  符合空气动力学的羽饰
Note, the feathers for aerodynamics,
能使敌军目眩的闪耀色彩
the sparkly color to dazzle the enemy,
纯属装饰性的靴子
the boots purely decorative.
还有这个
And this,
一把装有收音机的加特林机枪
this is a Gatling gun mounted with a radio
能够播放恼人的音乐来打击敌人
which emits annoying music to dishearten the enemy.
顺便说一下  这些都是有版权的
This is all copyrighted, by the way.
也就是说你不能盗版它们
That means you can't copy it.
没错  别打歪主意了  小子
Ja. Don't get any ideas, kid.
孩子们告诉我你爸爸在外打仗
The kids tell me that your father's away fighting.
所以现在你是家里的顶梁柱了  感觉怎么样
So it appears you are now the man of the house. How's that going?
还行吧
It's okay.
是吗
Ja?
你今天需要我做什么工作吗
So, what jobs do you have for me today?
说实话  有一份活
Well, I've got one, I won't lie.
跟你原来做的事情比  没那么重要
It's a bit of a step down from what you're used to,
但是我们现在需要所有的人手
but we need all hands on deck right now.
帮助祖国
需要金属
为希特勒捐金属
Metal for Hitler!
为打仗捐锅碗瓢盆
Pots and pans for the war effort!
? 金属小子来了 ?
? Here comes the metal man ?
? 收集锅碗盆瓢 ?
? Looking for your pots and pans ?
-为希特勒捐金属  -为希特勒捐金属
- Metal for Hitler! - Metal for Hitler!
螺栓螺钉
Nuts and bolts!
锅碗瓢盆
Pots and pans!
解放德国  反抗纳粹党
解放德国
"Free Germany."
乔乔
Jojo?
-约克  -你好
- Yorki? - Hi!
你当上士兵了
You're a soldier now?
乐意为你效劳
At your service.
但是你才十一岁
But you're only 11.
是啊
I know.
-我可以看看吗  -当然
- May I? - Yeah, sure.
这是纸做的吗
Is that paper?
我刚开始也是这么想的  但这只是看上去像纸
That's what I thought at first, too, but it's "paper-like."
这是由我们的顶尖科学家发明的最新材料
It's the latest material invented by our top scientists.
真了不起
Well, I'm impressed.
约克
Hey, Yorki.
我抓了个犹太人  真的
I caught a Jew. A real one.
犹太人
A Jew?
上个月我看到他们抓了几个藏在森林里的
I saw some that they caught hiding in the forest last month.
个人而言  我不明白有什么好大惊小怪的
Personally, I didn't see what all the fuss was about.
他们一点也不可怕  看上去就是普通人
They weren't at all scary and seemed kind of normal.
我还有任务呢
I'm getting distracted.
我得走了
I got to go.
再见
Bye.
-再见  -天呐
- Bye. - Oh, my God.
穿着这玩意太难跑了
It's so hard to run in this thing.
我找到了这些
I found these.
给你吧  大概都摔断了
You can have them. They're probably broken.
没什么大不了的
Doesn't mean anything.
也许你可以帮我的书画点东西
Maybe you can draw something for my book.
我可以再画一次你
I could draw you again.
没有人想看瘸子的画像
No one wants to see pictures of cripples.
你不算是瘸子
You're hardly a cripple.
再说  真正的艺术家看不见这些
Besides, true artists don't see that stuff.
你是说盲人艺术家吧
Blind artists, you mean.
没事的
It's fine.
我只能接受现实  我这辈子
I'll just accept I'll be one of those guys
永远没机会亲吻女孩
who'll never get to kiss a girl.
会有机会的  乔乔
You will be kissed, Jojo.
你想让我亲你吗
Do you want me to kiss you?
好了
Okay.
两件事
Two things.
第一件事
Thing number one:
纳粹和犹太人像我们这样相处是违法的
It's illegal for Nazis and Jews to hang out like we do,
更别说亲吻了
let alone kiss.
第二件事
Thing number two:
那只是同情的吻  不算数
It'd just be a sympathy kiss, which doesn't count.
你不是纳粹
You're not a Nazi.
我超级喜欢卍字
I'm massively into swastikas,
我觉得这就够明显了吧
so I think that's a pretty good sign right there.
你不是纳粹  乔乔
You're not a Nazi, Jojo.
你是个喜欢卍字
You're a ten-year-old kid who likes swastikas
喜欢穿可笑的制服
and likes dressing up in a funny uniform
想要被接纳的十岁小孩
and wants to be part of a club.
但是你跟他们不一样
But you are not one of them.
好吧
Okay.
我们保留意见吧
Let's just agree to disagree.
行吗
All right?
还说我不是纳粹
"Not a Nazi."
真是个脏兮兮的犹太佬
What a dirty Jew.
快  藏起来
Come on. Hide.
快点
Hurry. Go.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
请容我介绍一下我自己
Allow me to introduce myself.
我是法肯海姆盖世太保的
I'm Captain Herman Deertz
赫尔曼·迪尔茨上尉
of the Falkenheim Gestapo.
跟我一起的是  米勒先生  容克先生
With me, Herr Mueller, Herr Junker,
克鲁姆先生和福赫士先生  我们可以进去吗
Herr Klum and Herr Frosch. May we come in?
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler.
乔乔
Hey, Jojo!
大家好啊
Hey, guys!
很高兴见到你们
Good to see you!
我的自行车胎瘪了  所以我扛过来的
My bicycle got a flat tire, so I carried it.
-克伦森多夫上尉  希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Captain Klenzendorf. Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler.
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler.
你们都认识弗雷迪·芬克尔
You know Freddy Finkel.
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler.
我错过什么了吗
So, did I miss anything?
没有  我们刚刚才跟小孩打过招呼
No, no. We were just Heil Hitlering" The boy
还有跟你打了招呼
and then Heil Hitlering" Yourself
当然了  还跟弗雷迪·芬克尔打了招呼
and then, of course, Heil Hitlering" Freddy Finkel
现在我们正在进行例行检查
and now we are in the midst of a routine inspection.
你来这有何贵干呢  上尉
And, uh, what brings you here, Captain?
我们只是路过
Oh, we were just passing by
想着可以给孩子送些小册子
and we thought we'd drop off some pamphlets for the boy.
他为我们工作
He works for us.
-我知道了  -嗯
- I see. - Ja.
-那么你呢  -你知道的
- And yourself? - Oh, you know how it is.
每天我们都会接到电话  "你好  是盖世太保吗
Every day we take a call. "Hello, is that the Gestapo?
我觉得我的冰箱后面藏了个共产党"
I believe there's a Communist hiding behind my fridge."
然后我们去调查  发现只是长霉了
We go around to investigate. It's just some mold.
跟共产党差不多
So, not far off.
都是我工作的一部分
It's all part of the job.
我就喜欢这样的小男孩卧室
Now this is my kind of little boy's bedroom.
太棒了
Oh, yes.
他的海报
There he is.
你和朋友们可能听过谣言
You and your friends may have heard a rumor
说希特勒只有一个睾丸
that Hitler only has one ball.
简直是胡说八道
This is nonsense.
他有四个
He has four.
你在希特勒青年团做义工  对吗
So, you are volunteering at the Hitlerjugend office, yes?
对
Yes.
好样的
Good for you.
真希望有更多的小男孩像你一样盲目狂热
I wish more of our young boys had your blind fanaticism.
这些蠢货到底想干什么
What on Earth are those oafs up to?
不如我们到楼上去看看  好吗
Why don't we go upstairs and see, yes?
你知道你妈妈在哪吗
Do you know where your mother is?
不知道  应该是进城了
No. I think she's in town.
她最近在家的时间多吗
Has she been spending much time at home?
她很忙
She is quite busy.
是吗
Is she?
我很高兴看到你穿着
Well, I'm pleased to see that you're wearing your...
青年团制服
jugend uniform,
但是
but...
你的刀呢
where is your knife?
你必须随身携带青年团佩刀  你的刀呢
You must always carry your DJ knife. Where is it?
-我把它放在了  -在这
- I left it... - It's here.
你是哪位
And who might you be?
你又是哪位  你在我家干什么
Well, who might you be? And what are you doing in my house?
你也住在这吗
You live here too?
我是他姐姐  英格
I'm his sister, Inge.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
-希特勒万岁  -希特勒万岁
- Heil Hitler. - Heil Hitler.
我不知道你有姐姐  乔纳斯
I did not know you had a sister, Johannes.
有时候他巴不得我死了
Sometimes he'd prefer if I was dead.
对吧  小科学怪人
Isn't that right, little Frankenstein?
行了  没有必要
Now, now. There is no need to attack
攻击他丑陋的外表
his hideous physical deformity.
这是战争留下的伤痕
That is a war wound.
但是  为什么他的刀在你手上
But, uh, why do you have his knife?
我要守卫我的房间  因为他总是闯进来
I'm guarding my room because he refuses to stay out of it.
你在里面藏了什么
Well, what do you have hidden in there?
你也知道  女孩的东西
Oh, you know, girl stuff.
我可以进去吗
May I?
当然
Naturally.
我们要处理不计其数的举报
You see, we deal with an inordinate number of reports,
告发和普通调查
denunciations and general investigations.
当然  我们的确有兴趣
And, of course, we are indeed interested
处理犯罪和反党情绪
in problems of crime and anti-party sentiment,
但是我们最担心的
but we still have one greater concern,
出自童话故事《金发姑娘和三只熊》
就是"金发姑娘"
that of the "Goldilockses."
偷偷摸摸  吃别人的食物
Sneaking around, eating other people's food,
睡别人的床
sleeping in their beds.
实在是很没礼貌
It really is quite rude.
你应该不介意把证件给我看看吧
I don't suppose I could see your papers, could I?
证件  贝茨勒小姐  请快点
Papers, Miss Betzler. Quickly, please.
我们没那么多时间
We don't have all day.
好的  当然可以
Yes, of course.
英格·贝茨勒
这张照片几岁拍的
How old are you in this photo?
三年前拍的
They're three years old.
我当时十四岁
I was 14.
出生日期
Date of birth?
5月1日
First of May.
1929年
1929.
正确  谢谢  英格
Correct. Thank you, Inge.
去拍张新的  这张照片看着像鬼一样
Get a new photo. You look like a ghost in this one.
等等
Wait.
这是
What is...
什么
this?
喂  犹太佬
揭秘犹太人
《喂  犹太佬》
Yoohoo Jew.
告诉我  谁写的
Tell me, who did this?
是我
I did.
是揭秘犹太人的
It's an exposé on Jews.
他们的思想  行为以及长相
How they think, behave, look.
是送给元首的礼物
It'll be a gift to the Führer.
各位  你们一定要来看看这个
Guys, you have to see this.
看看这个  他有条尾巴
Oh, look at this one. He has a tail.
这个像蝙蝠一样倒挂着
There's one of them hanging upside down like a bat.
这一副  是头的画像
This one here, it is a drawing of their heads.
是谁在操控他们头脑内部的机器
And who is operating the machinery of their brains?
恶魔
The devil.
真有趣  因为这就是事实
It's funny 'cause it's true.
看看这个愚蠢的小犹太人
Look at this little, stupid Jew.
长着犄角
There they are with horns.
这是什么
What is this?
"去死吧  内森  去死吧"
"Die, Nathan, die."
"杀死内森的方法"
"Ways of killing Nathan."
内森被蛇折磨
Nathan being tortured by snakes.
被木棍捅
Poked with sticks.
被大炮发射出去
Being fired from a cannon
被辱骂
and just being called names.
内森被老式自行车的轮子压扁
Nathan being crushed under the wheel of an old-time penny-farthing bicycle.
请问谁是内森
Who is Nathan, please?
一个男孩
Just some boy.
内森被架在火上烤
Nathan being roasted over an open fire.
让我想起来我们得回去了
Reminds me, we must get back and...
-记得吗  那个人还被我们吊在那呢  -对对
- You remember? Cause we left that guy hanging up. - Ja. Ja.
感谢你的作品  能让我开心一整天
Thank you for this. You have really made my day.
希望你能继续写
I do hope you continue with it.
当然了
And, of course,
如果你看到可疑的人  给我们打电话
if you see anything suspicious, give us a ring.
再见
Good day.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
很高兴认识你  英格
Nice to meet you, Inge.
待在家里  乔乔
Stay home, Jojo.
照看好你的家人
Look after your family.
看好这把刀
Look after this knife.
爱莎  你骗过他们了
Elsa, you fooled them.
5月7日
May seventh.
什么
What?
她是5月7日出生的  不是5月1日
She was born on the seventh, not the first.
他帮了我们
He was helping us.
他们会回来的
They'll be back.
他们会查出来她已经死了  我也死定了
They'll figure out she's dead, then I'll be dead.
其实没人知道英格死了
Nobody really knows Inge died.
你可以当她
You could be her.
妈妈回家之后我就告诉她一切
I'll tell Mama everything when she gets home.
告诉她我认识你  我们是朋友
That I know you and that we're friends.
犹太人和纳粹不是朋友
Jew and Nazi are not friends.
天呐  彻头彻尾的失败
Man, that was a complete bust.
你能解释一下吗
You mind explaining that?
她不是
She's not...
她看起来不是坏人
She doesn't seem like a bad person.
我开始质疑你对我以及对党的忠诚了
I am beginning to question your loyalty to myself and the party.
你说自己是爱国者
You call yourself a patriot?
但证据在哪
Yet, where is the evidence?
德国士兵生来肩上就扛着重担
The German soldier was born out of necessity.
德国有赖于年轻人的激情
Germany depends on the passion of these young men.
随时准备为祖国献身的激情
Passion and the readiness to fall for the Fatherland
尽管投机取巧的同盟国徒劳反抗
despite the futile efforts of Allied war profiteers
派出准备不足的军队深入龙潭虎穴
who send their ill-prepared armies clumsily into the lair of the wolf.
只有那些勇敢地站到敌人面前的狂热分子
And only zealous men who stand steadfast in the face of the enemy
才能永远地被德国人铭记
will be etched in German memory forever.
现在由你来决定  是要被铭记
And it is up to you to decide if you want to be remembered,
还是消失在历史的洪流里
or disappear without a trace
就像一粒可悲的沙子掉进了毫无价值的沙漠
like a pitiful grain of sand into a desert of insignificance.
明确地告诉你
To put it plainly...
你得振作起来  轻重缓急拎拎清楚
get your shit together and sort out your priorities.
你已经十岁了  乔乔
You're ten, Jojo.
别再像个小孩子似的
Start acting like it.
来为希特勒青年团效力
解放德国  反抗纳粹党
不
No.
你知道她的身份吗
Did you know?
她没对我说太多
She didn't tell me much...
只是提到她和她的朋友一起行动
only that she worked with her friends
而你在远方的爸爸也有参与
and your father was somehow involved from afar.
不  他正在打仗
No. He's fighting in the war.
她说战争一结束他就会回家
She said he'll be home as soon as the war's over.
她说  很显然她不能告诉你这些
She didn't want to tell you anything for obvious reasons.
因为她恨我
Because she hated me.
因为我是个纳粹
'Cause I'm a Nazi.
我是她的敌人
I'm the enemy.
她不想让你知道
She didn't want you to know anything
因为那会让你惹上麻烦
that could get you in trouble.
可现在我一无所有
But now I have nothing.
孤身一人
No one.
我最后一次见到我的父母是在火车站
The last time I saw my parents was at the station.
他们被押上一辆火车
They were put on a train.
我逃跑了
I ran.
一点点找到回城市的路
Slowly found my way back to the city.
我一个朋友的爸爸把我藏了起来
A friend of my father's hid me.
之后藏在另一个朋友那里  之后是朋友的朋友
Then another friend, then friends of friends.
直到你妈妈收留了我
Until your mother took me in.
目前为止  我活下来了
And so far, I'm still here.
但是我的...
But my...
我的父母去了一个有去无回的地方
my parents went to a place you don't come back from.
你自由之后要做的第一件事是什么
What's the first thing you'll do when you're free?
跳舞
Dance.
? Everybody's gotta live ?
Everybody's Gotta Live - Love
? And everybody's gonna die ?
? Everybody's gotta live ?
? I think you know the reason why ?
? Sometimes the goin' gets so good ?
? Then again, it gets pretty rough ?
? But when I have you in my arms, baby ?
? You know I just can't, I just can't get enough ?
? Everybody's gotta live ?
? Yes, they do ?
? And everybody's gonna die ?
? Everybody try to have a, a good time ?
? I think you know the reason why ?
? I feel like I've seen just about a million sunsets ?
亲爱的爱莎
? She said if you're with me, I'll never go away ?
? That's when I stopped and I took another look at my baby ?
内森
? She said if you're with me, I'll never go away ?
? Because everybody's gotta live ?
? And everybody's gonna die ?
? Everybody's gotta live ?
? Before you know the reason why ?
就这样  就这样  快点
That's it. That's it. Hurry.
约克
Yorki?
乔乔
Jojo!
老天
Oh, God.
乔乔
Jojo.
我好想你
How I've missed you.
你妈妈的事我很遗憾
Sorry about your mama.
我听说了以后哭了很久
I cried for ages when I heard what happened.
出什么事了
What's going on out here?
是俄国人  乔乔  他们攻进来了
The Russians, Jojo. They're coming.
美国人从另一个方向也攻进来了
And the Americans from the other way.
还有英格兰  中国  非洲  印度
And England and China and Africa and India.
整个世界都攻进来了
The whole world is coming.
帮我搬一下弹药
Help me with this ammo.
-我们的军队呢  -很糟糕
- And how are we doing? - Terribly.
我们唯一的友军是日本人
Our only friends are the Japanese.
我就偷偷和你说
And just between you and me,
他们看起来可不像雅利安人
they don't look very Aryan.
-记得我跟你提过的那个犹太人吗  -记得
- Remember that Jew I told you about? - Yeah.
她还在我那
I still have her.
她现在差不多算是我的女友了
She's basically my girlfriend now.
挺厉害啊  乔乔  都有女友了
Good for you, Jojo. A girlfriend.
可是  你知道的  她是犹太人
But, you know, she's Jewish.
现在有比犹太人更严重的问题需要担心  乔乔
There are bigger things to worry about than Jews, Jojo.
这世界上还有俄国人
There's Russians somewhere out there.
他们比所有人都可怕
They're worse than anyone.
我听说他们会吃小孩  还会和狗性交
I heard they eat babies and have sex with dogs.
够邪恶了吧
I mean, like, that's bad, right?
和狗性交
Sex with dogs?
没错  英国佬也那么干
Yeah. The Englishmen do it, too.
我们得在他们吃掉我们
We have to stop them before
还有瞎搞我们的狗之前阻止他们
they eat us and screw all our dogs.
这太疯狂了
It's crazy.
如今希特勒死了  我们只能靠自己了
And now Hitler's gone, we're really on our own.
-你说什么  -你没听说吗
- What? - You didn't hear?
他死了
He's dead.
他放弃了  饮弹自尽
He gave up and blew his brains out.
不
No.
那不可能
That's impossible.
全崩出来了
Blew them out.
他的脑浆
His brains.
原来他对我们隐瞒了许多事情
Turns out he was hiding a lot of stuff from us.
瞒着所有人做了许多坏事
Doing some really bad things behind everyone's backs.
我不确定我们站对了队伍
I'm not sure we chose the right side.
好了  过来  好的
Okay. Come here. Okay.
看见那个美国人了吗
See that American there?
过去给他一个拥抱  去吧  跑起来  快去
Just go give him a hug. Go! Run! Let's go!
约克  约克  好消息
Yorki. Yorki, great news.
你刚刚被升职了  有了你自己的配枪
You've just been promoted, and you get your own pistol.
快去朝着所有和我们看起来不一样的人开枪
Just go and shoot anybody who looks different to us.
-去吧  -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
乔乔  你的制服呢
Jojo, where's your uniform?
来  穿上这件外套
Here. Here, put the jacket on
这样他们就不会对你开枪
so they know not to shoot you.
我们必须干掉我们看到的所有人
We must kill everything that we see.
为了希特勒
For Hitler.
去死吧  丑恶的人渣
Die, devil scum!
去死吧
Die!
散开
Fall out!
冲啊
Ja.
快来  这边走
Come. This way.
他们攻进来了
They are here!
美国人来了
The Americans!
快点
Come on.
-跟紧他  -在你后面  上尉
- Stay on him. - Behind you, Cap.
我来看看他
I'll check him.
小伙子们
Boys!
把战俘带走
Move the prisoners.
让战俘都排好队
Keep the prisoners all in line.
快点  动作快点
Quickly. Quickly!
什么
What?
我...我听不懂
I-I don't understand.
走  快点走
Move! Move!
起来  狗腿子
Get up, wretched dog.
克上尉
Captain K.
你好啊  孩子
Heya, kid.
瞧瞧这阵仗
Look at all this commotion, huh?
-出什么事了  -都疯了  小家伙
- What's happening? - Hysteria, my friend.
我们已经...我们已经走投无路了
We've come... We've come to the end.
-一切都完了  -不  我和他们不一样
- Party's over. - No, I'm not like them.
-你害怕吗  不要害怕  -不  求你了
- Are you scared? Don't be scared. - No. Please.
-看着我  -不  不
- Look at me. - No. No.
罗茜的事我很遗憾  她是个好人
I'm sorry about Rosie. She was a good person.
真正的好人
An actual good person.
知道吗
Okay?
没事的  孩子
It's okay, kid.
我一直想告诉你
I've been meaning to tell you.
我觉得你的书真的很棒
I think your book is really great.
真的  抱歉之前嘲笑它
Ja, I'm sorry for laughing at it.
非常有创造性
Very creative.
起来  让我看看你
Come here, let's take a look at you.
挺不错
You look good.
你没事  孩子
You're okay, kid.
回家吧  照顾好你那个姐姐
Now, go home. Look after that sister of yours.
好吗
Okay?
滚开  滚开  犹太佬
Get away. Get away, Jew.
-什么情况  -滚开
- What's going on? - Get away!
他是犹太佬
He's a Jew.
闭嘴  你认识这个纳粹吗
Shut up. You know this Nazi?
-他帮了我们  -我不认识这个肮脏的犹太佬
- He helped us. - No, I don't know this dirty Jew.
不  不
No, no...
滚开  犹太佬
Get away, Jew.
把嘴闭上  纳粹
Shut your mouth, Nazi.
-不  不  不  -离开这里  回家去
- No! No! No! - Get out of here. Go home.
-不  放开他  -回家去
- No! Leave him alone! - Go home!
不
No!
-放开我  -离开这里
- Get off! - Get out of here.
回家去
Go home!
乔乔
Jojo?
约克
Yorki!
谢天谢地  我还以为你死了
Thank God. I thought you were dead.
没有  我似乎永远死不了
No. It seems like I can never die.
我要回家看我妈妈
I'm gonna go home and see my mother.
我需要一个拥抱
I need a cuddle.
-一切都乱套了  -是啊  我知道
- Nothing makes sense anymore. - Ja, I know.
绝对不是当纳粹的好时候
It's definitely not a good time to be a Nazi.
现在战争结束了
So now the war's over,
至少你的女友自由了
at least your girlfriend will be free.
她可以离开了
She can leave now.
有问题吗
Something wrong?
我得走了
I've got to go.
-好的  -抱歉
- Okay. - Sorry.
回见
Later!
我回来了
I'm home.
外面什么情况
What's going on out there?
-外面哪里  -街上  傻瓜
- Out where? - Outside, dummy.
乔乔  什么情况
Jojo, what's going on?
出去安全吗
Is it safe to come out?
乔乔  安全吗
Jojo, is it safe?
我能离开吗
Can I leave?
不
No.
你不能离开
You can't leave.
为什么
Why?
你必须待在这里
You have to stay here...
谁赢了
Who won?
和我一起
with me.
乔乔  谁打赢了战争
Jojo, who won... who won the war?
我们赢了
We did.
德国赢了
Germany won the war.
我很抱歉
I-I'm sorry.
喂  犹太佬
揭秘犹太人
亲爱的爱莎
"Dear Elsa.
我知道现在对你来说很艰难
"I know it's hard for you at the moment...
我知道你想要放弃
"And I know you feel like giving up.
但你必须坚持下去
"But you have to carry on.
我和你的好朋友乔乔
"Me and your good friend, Jojo,
设计了一个计划帮你逃脱
"Have devised a plan for you to escape.
所以请听他的话
"So, please listen to him.
他会帮你离开那里
"He's gonna help you get out of there.
然后你可以来巴黎和我住
"And then you can come live with me in Paris.
别担心乔乔
"And don't worry about Jojo.
他会没事的
"He'll be okay.
巴黎见
"See you in Paris.
内森
Nathan."
-他死了  -什么
- He's dead. - Pardon?
内森
Nathan.
他去年死了
He died last year.
肺结核
Tuberculosis.
那可真奇怪
Well... that's weird.
这些信是谁写的
Who wrote these?
谢谢你  乔乔
Thank you, Jojo.
你一直都对我很好
You have been so good to me.
其实
Well, the thing is,
我爱你
I love you.
我知道你把我当弟弟
I know you think of me as a younger brother,
这没问题
which is fine,
反正你年纪也太大了
and, you're too old anyway.
不过
But...
天  这里好热
Man, it's quite hot in here.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
-当弟弟爱  -当弟弟爱
- As a younger brother. - As a younger brother.
我和假内森真的有帮你逃脱的办法
Look, me and fake Nathan have found a way for you to escape.
或许你可以信任弟弟
Maybe you can trust a younger brother?
或许
Maybe.
那好
Okay, then.
收拾好你的东西
Get your things together.
我们要走了
We're leaving.
乔乔·贝茨勒
Jojo Betzler.
十岁半
Ten and a half years old.
今天
Today,
你要尽你所能
just do what you can.
你他妈的想去哪啊
Where in the shit do you think you're going, hmm?
-出去  -出去  不行
- Out. - Out? No, you don't.
不  我们要待在这里
No, we're gonna stay in here
你要一五一十地告诉我
and you're gonna tell me exactly what's going on
你和阁楼里那东西是怎么回事
with you and that thing in the attic.
那"东西"是个女孩
That "thing" is a girl.
-你爱上她了  是吗  -是的
- You're in love with her, aren't you? - Yes.
-承认吧  -我说了是的
- Admit it. - I just said yes.
我就知道
I knew it!
你们永远不可能
Well, it's never gonna work out.
不  她对你来说年纪太大
No. No, she's too old for you.
而且你很丑陋
And you're ugly.
你知道她会离开你的  对吧
You know she's gonna leave you. You know that, don't you?
接下来这样  你个小混球
So, here's what's gonna happen, you little shit.
你戴上这个
You're gonna put this on, okay?
忘记上面那个恶心的犹太佬
You're gonna forget about that disgusting Jewy cow up there.
回到我身边  这是你的归属
And you're gonna come back to me, where you belong.
明白吗
Right?
戴上
Put it on.
然后我们假装这一切都没发生过
And then, we're gonna pretend none of this ever happened.
懂了吗
You got it?
你不向我致敬吗
You're not gonna heil me?
快啊  看在过去的份上
Come on? For old time's sake?
-向我致敬  小家伙  -不
- Heil me, little man. - No.
-向我致敬  -不
- Heil me. - No.
小小致敬一下  就一小下  拜托
Give me a little heil. Just a little heil. Please?
滚蛋  希特勒
Fuck off, Hitler.
走吧
Come on.
等等
Wait.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
外面危险吗
Is it dangerous out there?
极其危险
Extremely.
耶
Yeah!
我们成功了
We made it.
我活该
Probably deserved that.
现在我们做什么
What do we do now?
接受一切的发生
美好与恐怖
坚持下去
没有不变的情感
-赖内·马利亚·里尔克